# **Dhruv Gajjar**

(847) 890-1847

dgajjar2@illinois.edu

#### **SUMMARY**

Engineering Physics major who is a quick learner, highly analytical, and an efficient problem solver. Has experience in data analysis and automation, Mechanical Engineering design project, and construction and engineering in the energy distribution industry.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# WEC Energy Group/Peoples Gas (Chicago, IL) Performance Engineering Intern

May 2018 - Aug 2018

Website: https://dhruvgajjar.github.io

Social: www.linkedin.com/in/dhruv-gajjar-5111b6125

- Developed a demo database using Microsoft SQL Server to introduce using databases within the Engineering Department as opposed to pulling data from Microsoft Sharepoint or other online file-sharing platforms
- Designed VBA programs to rapidly pull data from thousands of sources in multiple directories that assisted in cost analysis for future consultant contract negotiations and budget forecasting based on current spending
- Assumed a data analyst role; led an initiative to automate and standardize multiple processes and data sources in the Engineering and Contracts department for better record keeping and future analysis
- Examined proposed plans by other utilities submitted to Chicago's utility regulatory office to determine possible conflicts with the company's existing pipelines and facilities

# WEC Energy Group/Peoples Gas (Chicago, IL) Distribution Engineering Intern

Jun 2017 - Aug 2017

- Designed an automated quality assurance VBA program for job-site measurements; this program is still currently utilized as
  a tool by a two teams of engineers
- Walked through projects issued for construction in planned neighborhoods to determine if they complied with regulation
- o Ran gas flow simulations for proposed pipelines to determine if construction would be feasible and non-intrusive to area
- o Implemented pipeline retirements on the company's mapping software once new pipe was installed

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

**Expected Graduation: Dec 2018** 

B.S. in Engineering Physics; Specialization in Mechanical Engineering GPA: 3.37/4.00

#### **PROJECTS**

### Personal Professional Website

- Built a website to showcase my experience and accomplishments while also applying my HTML, CSS, and Javascript skills
- Mass Produced Electro-Mechanical Invention/Innovation; Course Name: Computer Aided Design
  - Collaborated in a team of three to create a product that solves a common problem. Designed an easy-to-use clothing iron attached to an ironing board which is ideal for tight spaces or frequent travelers. Deliverables included: 3D CAD models, engineering drawings, and a cost analysis of materials and manufacturing processes used

#### **VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE**

# Alpha Phi Omega Service Events

Jan 2017 - Present

- Held three leadership positions within the fraternity and completed 85+ hours of community service
- Math and Physics Tutor

Aug 2014 - May 2016

Tutored students in high school and college-level math and physics

## **EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES & AWARDS**

Alpha Phi Omega Service Fraternity

Jan 2017 - Present

• Illinois Student Assistance Commission Scholar

Jun 2015

Prairie State Achievement Award: Reading, Mathematics, and Science

Jun 2015

## **SKILLS & CERTIFICATIONS**

- **Software:** Autodesk Inventor, Microsoft Access, Microsoft SQL Server, Synergi Gas, Creo Parametric 3.0, ESRI, ArcGIS, Git, and high-level proficiency in Microsoft Excel, Word, and Powerpoint
- Programming Languages: Visual Basic/VBA, Python, MATLAB, HTML, CSS, Javascript, and SQL
- Languages: English (Native Proficiency), Hindi (Intermediate)
- Certifications: GTI Pipeline Safety Regulatory Compliance Course